[{"Question":"What are the symptoms of COVID-19?","Answer":"#### **[**Coronavirus symptoms**](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/symptoms-testing/symptoms.html) **include, but are not limited to:****\\n\\n*   Fever or chills\\n*   Cough\\n*   Shortness of breath or difficulty breathing\\n*   Fatigue\\n*   Muscle or body aches\\n*   Headache\\n*   New loss of taste or smell\\n*   Sore throat\\n*   Congestion or runny nose\\n*   Nausea or vomiting\\n*   Diarrhea\\n\\nMore info: [Symptoms and risks](https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"1"},{"Question":"Is there a COVID-19 symptoms self-checker?","Answer":"You can check your symptoms using the [Symptom Screener](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/symptoms-testing/symptoms.html?CDC_AA_refVal=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cdc.gov%2Fcoronavirus%2F2019-ncov%2Fsymptoms-testing%2Findex.html) or by contacting your doctor through [telehealth](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/).\\n\\nMore info: [Symptoms and risks](https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"2"},{"Question":"Who are high risk people for COVID-19?","Answer":"#### ****Some people are at higher risk to get very sick from COVID-19, including:****\\n\\n*   people over 65 years old\\n*   people with compromised immune systems\\n*   Individuals who have serious chronic medical conditions like:\\n    *   Heart disease\\n    *   Diabetes\\n    *   Lung disease\\n*   [Smokers](https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2002032)\\n\\nMore info: [Symptoms and risks](https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"3"},{"Question":"What people at higher risk, over 65 or compromised immune systems, should do?","Answer":"If you are at higher risk, you should take extra precautions to protect yourself: \\n\\n*   **Stay home.** It’s the most important thing you can do.\\n*   **Avoid contact with people who are sick.** Isolate anyone sick in your home in a separate room, if possible.\\n*   **Get food brought to your house** through family, social, or commercial networks. Wipe off containers with disinfectant wipes.\\n*   **Listen to public health officials.** They may recommend community actions to reduce exposure in times of local outbreak.\\n\\nMore info: [Symptoms and risks](https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"4"},{"Question":"What’s open statewide?","Answer":"**Essential services** that protect public health, public safety, and provide essential needs will remain open, such as:\\n\\n*   Gas stations \\n*   Pharmacies\\n*   Food: Grocery stores, farmers markets, food banks, convenience stores, take-out and delivery restaurants \\n*   Banks \\n*   Laundromats/laundry services \\n*   Childcare\\n*   Essential state and local government functions will also remain open, including law enforcement and offices that provide government programs and services.\\n\\n**Retailers** can open statewide. All will require modifications to support social distancing. This includes:\\n\\n*   Shopping malls\\n*   Libraries\\n*   Movie theaters and drive-in theaters (with modifications)\\n*   Bookstores\\n*   Jewelry stores\\n*   Toy stores\\n*   Clothing and shoe stores\\n*   Home and furnishing stores\\n*   Sporting goods stores\\n*   Florists\\n\\n**Offices** (in all sectors, not only critical infrastructure)\\n\\n**Limited services** which do not generally require close customer contact, such as: \\n\\n*   Pet grooming\\n*   Dog walking\\n*   Car washes\\n*   Appliance repair\\n*   Residential and janitorial cleaning\\n*   Places of worship\\n*   Plumbing\\n\\n**Outdoor museums**\\n\\n**Music, film, and TV production**\\n\\n**Professional sports (without live audiences)**\\n\\n**Schools and day camps**\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"7"},{"Question":"What’s closed statewide?","Answer":"Statewide, the following are still closed:\\n\\n*   Personal services, like nail salons, body waxing and tattoo parlors\\n*   Public events and gatherings, like live audience sports \\n*   Convention centers\\n*   Theme parks and festivals\\n*   Higher education (in person)\\n*   Indoor playgrounds, like bounce centers, ball pits and laser tag\\n*   Saunas and steam rooms\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"8"},{"Question":"What is open with county variance?","Answer":"The following may open only in [counties approved to move further in the Resilience Roadmap](https://www.cdph.ca.gov/Programs/CID/DCDC/Pages/COVID-19/County_Variance_Attestation_Form.aspx):\\n\\n*   Dine-in restaurants\\n*   Hair salons and barber shops\\n*   Casinos\\n\\nCounties that are approved to progress further into the Resilience Roadmap can decide to open the following industries but are strongly encouraged to wait until June 12, 2020:\\n\\n*   Family entertainment centers\\n*   Restaurants, wineries and bars\\n*   Zoos and museums\\n*   Gyms and fitness centers\\n*   Hotels (for tourism and individual travel)\\n*   Cardrooms and racetracks\\n*   Campgrounds and outdoor recreation\\n\\nCounties that are approved to progress further into the Resilience Roadmap can decide to open the following industries but are strongly encouraged to wait until June 19, 2020:\\n\\n*   Personal services, like nail salons, body waxing and tattoo parlors\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"9"},{"Question":"Is it safe to shop at open businesses?","Answer":"The risk of COVID-19 infection is still real for all Californians and continues to be fatal. That is why every business permitted to open should take every step humanly possible to reduce the risk of infection by following these [state guidelines](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap/).\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"10"},{"Question":"Are mass gatherings permitted?","Answer":"State public health directives prohibit professional, social and community mass gatherings. Gatherings are defined as—meetings or other events that bring together persons from multiple households at the same time for a shared or group experience in a single room, space, or place such as an auditorium, stadium, arena, large conference room, meeting hall, or other indoor or outdoor space. They pose an especially high danger of transmission and spread of COVID-19.\\n\\nOn May 25, 2020, in an effort to balance First Amendment interests with public health, the State Public Health Officer created an exception to the prohibition against mass gatherings for faith-based services and cultural ceremonies as well as protests. Those types of gatherings are permitted so long as they do not exceed 100 attendees or 25% of the capacity of the space in which the gathering is held, whichever is lower. All other mass gatherings are prohibited until further notice.\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"14"},{"Question":"Can I get a haircut?","Answer":"It depends. If your county has been approved to move further in the Resilience Roadmap, then hair salons and barber shops may reopen in your area. See the list of [counties with a variance](https://www.cdph.ca.gov/Programs/CID/DCDC/Pages/COVID-19/County_Variance_Attestation_Form.aspx).\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"15"},{"Question":"Can I visit my family and friends?","Answer":"It is best to stay connected with your loved ones through phone and video calls, as visiting family and friends outside your household still presents a risk of spreading coronavirus. Keeping distance from others is especially important for people that are at higher risk of getting very sick, including older people, and people of any age who have underlying medical conditions. \\n\\nIf you do visit family or friends that don’t live in your home in person, take steps to keep everyone safe, like:\\n\\n*   Keep at least 6 feet between yourself and others, even when you wear a face covering\\n*   Visit outdoors instead of indoors when possible\\n*   Wear a face covering or cloth mask\\n*   Wash your hands often\\n*   Clean and disinfect commonly- touched surfaces\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"16"},{"Question":"I want to express my political views.  How can I make my voice heard?","Answer":"There are many ways for you to express your political views without holding a physical, in-person gathering.  For example, you may continue to call or write elected officials, write letters to the editor of news publications, display lawn or window signs, or use online and other electronic media (including Zoom rooms, Twitter feeds, Facebook pages, and other digital forums) to express your views.  \\n\\nAdditionally, as noted above, you may leave your home for any reason as long as you **do not gather with people who are not members of your household**.  When you are otherwise out in public, public health directives do not prevent you from engaging in political expression—such as by wearing or carrying a sign.\\n\\nIf collective action in physical space is important to you, consider whether you and other participants can safely protest from within your cars.  The State Public Health Officer does not consider in-car protests to be gatherings, if participants stay in their cars and otherwise remain apart from individuals who are not part of their households.  Many activists have organized car-based protests (honking horns, flying flags, displaying signs, and so on) to express their political views while complying with State public health directives.  \\n\\nWhenever you are considering a protest (including an in-car protest), make sure you comply with all other applicable laws, including any local public-health measures that may be more restrictive than statewide directives and any other applicable local laws.\\n\\nIf you do wish to engage in in-person protest outside of your car with a group of any size, you must follow the guidelines for political protest gatherings below.\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"17"},{"Question":"Can I engage in political protest gatherings?","Answer":"Yes, although in-person protests present special public health concerns. \\n\\nEven with adherence to physical distancing, bringing members of different households together to engage in in-person protest carries a higher risk of widespread transmission of COVID-19.  Such gatherings may result in increased rates of infection, hospitalization, and death, especially among more vulnerable populations. In particular, activities like chanting, shouting, singing, and group recitation negate the risk-reduction achieved through six feet of physical distancing. For this reason, people engaging in these activities should wear face coverings at all times.\\n\\nTherefore, it is strongly recommended that those exercising their right to engage in political expression (including, for example, their right to petition the government) should utilize alternative channels, such as the many online and broadcasting platforms available in the digital age, in place of in-person gatherings. \\n\\nHowever, state public health directives do not prohibit in-person _outdoor_ protests as long as physical distancing of six feet between persons or groups of persons from different households is maintained at all times. Additionally, Local Health Officers are advised to consider appropriate limitations on outdoor attendance capacities, factoring their jurisdiction’s key COVID-19 health indicators. Failure to maintain adequate physical distancing may result in an order to disperse or other enforcement action. Masks and cloth face coverings are strongly recommended.\\n\\nState public health directives do not prohibit in-person _indoor_ protests as long as (1) attendance is limited to 25% of the relevant area’s maximum occupancy, as defined by the relevant local permitting authority or other relevant authority, or a maximum of 100 attendees, whichever is lower, and (2) physical distancing of six feet between persons or groups of persons from different households is maintained at all times. Failure to maintain adequate physical distancing may result in an order to disperse or other enforcement action. Masks and cloth face coverings are strongly recommended.\\n\\nParticipants must maintain a physical distance of six feet from any uniformed peace officers and other public safety personnel present, unless otherwise directed, and follow all other requirements and directives imposed by local health officers and law enforcement, or other applicable authorities.\\n\\nThis limitation on attendance will be reviewed at least once every 21 days. This review will assess the impacts of these imposed limits on public health and provide further direction as part of a phased-in restoration of gatherings that implicate the First Amendment.\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"18"},{"Question":"Can I go to church?","Answer":"Yes. As of May 25, places of worship such as churches, mosques, temples, and synagogues can open throughout the state, with [modifications for safety (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-places-of-worship.pdf).\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"20"},{"Question":"Can I travel?","Answer":"You can travel for urgent matters or if such travel is essential to your permitted work. Even though businesses around the state are opening up, avoid travelling long distances for vacations or pleasure as much as possible. This is to slow the spread of the coronavirus. Do not travel if you are sick, or if someone in your household has had coronavirus in the last two weeks. Do not travel with someone who is sick.\\n\\nBefore travelling away from your community, consider these questions from the [Center for Disease Control (CDC) travel guidance](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/travelers/travel-in-the-us.html):\\n\\n*   Is coronavirus spreading where you are traveling?\\n*   Are you or those you are traveling with more likely to get very sick from coronavirus?\\n*   Will you be able to keep 6 feet of physical distance from others during or after your trip?\\n\\nIf you do travel, take steps to keep everyone safe like wearing a face cloth covering, keeping 6 feet of physical distance from those not in your household, and washing your hands frequently.  \\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"28"},{"Question":"Can I get my smog checked?","Answer":"The [Bureau of Automotive Repair](https://www.bar.ca.gov/COVID-19_Impacts_on_BAR_Programs_and_Services.aspx) advises drivers to still pay DMV vehicle registration fees to avoid any late fees. However, you will not receive your new registration or year sticker until the smog information has been received by DMV. Once state and local orders or directives are no longer in effect, consumers can then obtain the required smog check certificate to complete the DMV vehicle registration process.\\n\\nMore info: [Stay home Q&A](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"30"},{"Question":"What if I don’t have health insurance and I need screening,  testing, or treatment for COVID-19?","Answer":"The cost of coronavirus screening, testing, and treatment for the uninsured is paid for by the [government](https://www.hrsa.gov/CovidUninsuredClaim). You can check your symptoms using the [Symptom Screener](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/symptoms-testing/symptoms.html?CDC_AA_refVal=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cdc.gov%2Fcoronavirus%2F2019-ncov%2Fsymptoms-testing%2Findex.html) or by contacting your doctor through [telehealth](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/). You can also get free [testing](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/) through [Verily’s Project Baseline](https://www.projectbaseline.com/study/covid-19/eligibility/) or [OptumServe](https://lhi.care/covidtesting).\\n\\nMore info: [Health care coverage](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"34"},{"Question":"What about routine, elective, or non-urgent medical appointments?","Answer":"Preventive care services and non-emergency surgeries, like organ replacements and tumor removals, can take place if hospitals have enough capacity and protective equipment to do so safely. Eye exams, and elective procedures should be cancelled or rescheduled. If possible, health care visits should be done remotely. Dental services and preventive dental care may be resumed. Contact your doctor through [telehealth](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/) to see what services they are providing.\\n\\nMore info: [Health care coverage](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"42"},{"Question":"Can I leave home to care for my elderly parents or friends who require assistance? Or a friend or family member who has disabilities?","Answer":"Yes. Be sure that you protect them and yourself by following physical distancing guidelines such as wearing a mask, washing hands before and after, using hand sanitizer, maintaining at least six feet of distance when possible, and covering your cough or sneeze. If you have early signs of a cold, please stay away from your older loved ones.\\n\\nMore info: [Health care coverage](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"46"},{"Question":"What precautions should healthcare workers and organizations take?","Answer":"See [Cal/OSHA’s guidance on protecting workers from coronavirus](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dosh/coronavirus/Health-Care-General-Industry.html).\\n\\nMore info: [Businesses and employers](https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"76"},{"Question":"My school provides free grab-and-go meals. Are those still available?","Answer":"Yes. It is essential to keep children fed. Check with your local school district for days and times meals are offered.\\n\\nMore info: [Education](https://covid19.ca.gov/education/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/education/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"79"},{"Question":"Will there be a rent freeze or waiver for renters? Are evictions allowed during the stay at home order?","Answer":"There is an [order](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/03/16/governor-newsom-issues-executive-order-to-protect-renters-and-homeowners-during-covid-19-pandemic/) in place to halt evictions and protect renters. If you are financially affected by COVID-19 and [can’t pay your full rent](https://bcsh.ca.gov/coronavirus19/graphic_rent.pdf), let your landlord know in writing within seven days of the rent due date. Save documentation as proof. The order does not relieve you from the obligation to pay rent. It also does not restrict the landlord from recovering rent that is due.\\n\\nMore info: [Housing and Homelessness](https://covid19.ca.gov/housing-and-homelessness/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/housing-and-homelessness/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"106"},{"Question":"Can landlords delay their payments while their tenants cannot pay rent?","Answer":"Yes, there are protections in effect through July 28, 2020 for landlords. The [order](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/03/16/governor-newsom-issues-executive-order-to-protect-renters-and-homeowners-during-covid-19-pandemic/) requests lenders to halt foreclosures and related evictions during this time. Property owners should contact their financial institutions.\\n\\nMore info: [Housing and Homelessness](https://covid19.ca.gov/housing-and-homelessness/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/housing-and-homelessness/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"107"},{"Question":"How can I find help paying for childcare?","Answer":"[MyChildCare.ca.gov](http://mychildcare.ca.gov/) provides information on all licensed center-based and family childcare homes. This includes both private-pay and subsidized childcare. Children of essential workers are now eligible to enroll in subsidized emergency childcare through June 30, 2020. This is subject to capacity and eligibility requirements. Your [local childcare resource and referral agency](https://rrnetwork.org/index.php?p=family-services/find-child-care) can answer more questions about childcare subsidies.\\n\\nMore info: [Find childcare options near you](https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"110"},{"Question":"Can I get childcare during the stay home order?","Answer":"Yes, all childcare facilities can open with necessary modifications.\\n\\nMore info: [Find childcare options near you](https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"111"},{"Question":"Counties:","Answer":"*   [Alameda County](http://www.acphd.org/2019-ncov.aspx)\\n*   [Alpine County](http://alpinecountyca.gov/Index.aspx?NID=516)\\n*   [Amador County](https://www.amadorgov.org/services/covid-19)\\n*   [Butte County](https://www.buttecounty.net/publichealth)\\n*   [Calaveras County](https://covid19.calaverasgov.us/)\\n*   [Colusa County](https://www.countyofcolusa.org/99/Public-Health)\\n*   [Contra Costa County](https://www.coronavirus.cchealth.org/)\\n*   [Del Norte County](http://www.co.del-norte.ca.us/departments/health-human-services/public-health)\\n*   [El Dorado County](https://www.edcgov.us/Government/hhsa/Pages/EDCCOVID-19.aspx)\\n*   [Fresno County](https://www.co.fresno.ca.us/departments/public-health/covid-19)\\n*   [Glenn County](https://www.countyofglenn.net/dept/health-human-services/public-health/covid-19)\\n*   [Humboldt County](https://humboldtgov.org/2018/Humboldt-Health-Alert)\\n*   [Imperial County](http://www.icphd.org/health-information-and-resources/healthy-facts/covid-19/)\\n*   [Inyo County](https://www.inyocounty.us/coronavirus-covid-19-response)\\n*   [Kern County](https://kernpublichealth.com/2019-novel-coronavirus/)\\n*   [Kings County](https://www.countyofkings.com/departments/health-welfare/public-health/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19/-fsiteid-1)\\n*   [Lake County](http://health.co.lake.ca.us/Coronavirus.htm)\\n*   [Lassen County](http://www.co.lassen.ca.us/)\\n*   [Los Angeles County](http://publichealth.lacounty.gov/media/Coronavirus/)\\n*   [Madera County](https://www.maderacounty.com/government/public-health/health-updates/corona-virus)\\n*   [Marin County](https://coronavirus.marinhhs.org/)\\n*   [Mariposa County](http://www.mariposacounty.org/1592/COVID-19-Information)\\n*   [Mendocino County](https://www.mendocinocounty.org/community/novel-coronavirus)\\n*   [Merced County](https://www.co.merced.ca.us/3350/Coronavirus-Disease-2019)\\n*   [Modoc County](http://www.co.modoc.ca.us/)\\n*   [Mono County](https://coronavirus.monocounty.ca.gov/)\\n*   [Monterey County](https://www.co.monterey.ca.us/government/departments-a-h/health/diseases/2019-novel-coronavirus-covid-19)\\n*   [Napa County](https://www.countyofnapa.org/2739/Coronavirus)\\n*   [Nevada County](https://www.mynevadacounty.com/2924/Coronavirus)\\n*   [Orange County](https://www.ochealthinfo.com/phs/about/epidasmt/epi/dip/prevention/novel_coronavirus)\\n*   [Placer County](https://www.placer.ca.gov/coronavirus)\\n*   [Plumas County](https://www.plumascounty.us/2669/Novel-Coronavirus-2019-COVID-19)\\n*   [Riverside County](https://www.rivcoph.org/coronavirus)\\n*   [Sacramento County](https://dhs.saccounty.net/PUB/Pages/PUB-Home.aspx)\\n*   [San Benito County](https://hhsa.cosb.us/publichealth/communicable-disease/coronavirus/)\\n*   [San Bernardino County](http://wp.sbcounty.gov/dph/coronavirus/)\\n*   [San Diego County](https://www.sandiegocounty.gov/coronavirus.html)\\n*   [San Francisco City and County](https://sf.gov/topics/coronavirus-covid-19)\\n*   [San Joaquin County](https://www.sjgov.org/covid19/)\\n*   [San Luis Obispo County](https://www.emergencyslo.org/en/covid19.aspx)\\n*   [San Mateo County](https://www.smchealth.org/coronavirus)\\n*   [Santa Barbara County](https://publichealthsbc.org/)\\n*   [Santa Clara County](https://www.sccgov.org/sites/phd/DiseaseInformation/novel-coronavirus/Pages/home.aspx)\\n*   [Santa Cruz County](https://www.santacruzhealth.org/HSAHome/HSADivisions/PublicHealth/CommunicableDiseaseControl/Coronavirus.aspx)\\n*   [Shasta County](https://www.co.shasta.ca.us/index/hhsa/health-safety/current-heath-concerns/coronavirus)\\n*   [Sierra County](http://sierracounty.ca.gov/582/Coronavirus-COVID-19)\\n*   [Siskiyou County](https://www.co.siskiyou.ca.us/publichealth/page/coronavirus-covid-19-what-siskiyou-county-residents-need-know)\\n*   [Solano County](http://www.solanocounty.com/depts/ph/ncov.asp)\\n*   [Sonoma County](https://socoemergency.org/emergency/novel-coronavirus/)\\n*   [Stanislaus County](http://schsa.org/publichealth/pages/corona-virus/)\\n*   [Sutter County](https://www.suttercounty.org/doc/government/depts/cao/em/coronavirus)\\n*   [Tehama County](https://www.tehamacohealthservices.net/services/communicable-diseases/#current-events)\\n*   [Trinity County](https://www.trinitycounty.org/)\\n*   [Tulare County](https://tchhsa.org/eng/index.cfm/public-health/covid-19-updates-novel-coronavirus/)\\n*   [Tuolumne County](https://www.tuolumnecounty.ca.gov/250/Public-Health)\\n*   [Ventura County](https://www.vcemergency.com/)\\n*   [Yolo County](https://www.yolocounty.org/health-human-services/adults/communicable-disease-investigation-and-control/novel-coronavirus-2019)\\n*   [Yuba County](https://www.yuba.org/coronavirus/)\\n\\nMore info: [Get local information](https://covid19.ca.gov/state-local-resources/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/state-local-resources/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"113"},{"Question":"How is the state protecting incarcerated people in California?","Answer":"[California Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation (CDCR)](https://www.cdcr.ca.gov/covid19/) are dedicated to the safety of everyone who lives in, works in, and visits state prisons. CDCR has given all staff and inmates 2 reusable cloth masks to wear while moving between cells, dorms, meetings with others, or health care appointments. CDCR has also developed density and health care guidance to protect all inmates and staff, and has suspended volunteer services and in-person visiting.\\n\\nMore info: [Get local information](https://covid19.ca.gov/state-local-resources/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/state-local-resources/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"116"},{"Question":"Who can I contact about my child custody order and child visitation rights?","Answer":"Court operations vary from county to county. Please reach out to your [local government office](https://www.courts.ca.gov/find-my-court.htm?query=browse_courts) for more information. \\n\\nMore info: [Get local information](https://covid19.ca.gov/state-local-resources/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/state-local-resources/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"117"},{"Question":"Youth and Teens","Answer":"*   [California Youth Crisis Line](https://calyouth.org/cycl/)**:** Youth ages 12-24 can call or text [800-843-5200](tel:800-843-5200) or [chat online](https://m2.icarol.com/ConsumerRegistration.aspx?org=53141&pid=326&cc=en-US) for 24/7 crisis support.\\n*   [TEEN LINE](https://teenlineonline.org/talk-now/): Teens can talk to another teen by texting “TEEN” to [839863](sms:839863) from 6pm – 9pm, or call [800-852-8336](tel:800-852-8336) from 6pm – 10pm.\\n\\nMore info: [Resources for emotional support and well-being](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"128"},{"Question":"Veterans","Answer":"[Veterans Crisis Line](https://www.veteranscrisisline.net): Call [800-273-8255](tel:800-273-8255) and Press 1 or text [838255](sms:838255) for 24/7 support.\\n\\nMore info: [Resources for emotional support and well-being](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"129"},{"Question":"First Responders and Law Enforcement","Answer":"*   [Fire/EMS helpline](https://www.nvfc.org/fireems-helpline/): Call [888-731-FIRE](tel:888-731-FIRE) to get 24/7 help for a variety of behavioral health issues.\\n*   [COPLINE](https://www.copline.org/): Call [800-267-5463](tel:800-267-5463) to find support 24/7 for law enforcement officers.\\n\\nMore info: [Resources for emotional support and well-being](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"130"},{"Question":"Older Californians","Answer":"*   [Friendship Line](https://www.ioaging.org/services/all-inclusive-health-care/friendship-line): Call [888-670-1360](tel:888-670-1360) for 24/7 support if you are 60 years or older, or an adult living with disabilities.  \\n*   California Aging and Adult Information Line: Call [800-510-2020](tel:800-510-2020) for help finding local assistance. \\n\\nMore info: [Resources for emotional support and well-being](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"131"},{"Question":"Deaf and Hard of Hearing Individuals","Answer":"[National Suicide Prevention Deaf and Hard of Hearing Hotline](https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/help-yourself/for-deaf-hard-of-hearing/): Access 24/7 video relay service by dialing [800-273-8255](tel:800-273-8255) (TTY [800-799-4889](tel:800-799-4889)).\\n\\nMore info: [Resources for emotional support and well-being](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"132"},{"Question":"Services for Substance Use Disorders","Answer":"*   [SAMHSA National Helpline](https://www.samhsa.gov/find-help/national-helpline): Call [800-662-HELP](tel:1-800-662-4357) for 24/7 information and referrals in English and Spanish. \\n*   [SAMHSA Treatment Locator](https://findtreatment.samhsa.gov)**:**  Find drug or alcohol treatment programs. \\n*   [Local county access lines](https://gcc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dhcs.ca.gov%2Findividuals%2FPages%2FSUD_County_Access_Lines.aspx&data=02%7C01%7CJanne.Olson-Morgan%40osg.ca.gov%7C122307be91754d12e5dc08d7d984f958%7C265c2dcd2a6e43aab2e826421a8c8526%7C0%7C0%7C637217037446186621&sdata=5sx4UdIlVkRL%2BEJR7FrpK0gYAn20yE71TyBDFIw1kJM%3D&reserved=0): Find your local number for help seeking substance use disorder services.\\n\\nMore info: [Resources for emotional support and well-being](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"133"},{"Question":"LGBTQ Individuals","Answer":"*   [Trevor Project](https://www.thetrevorproject.org): Call [866-488-7386](tel:866-488-7386) or text START to [678678](sms:678678) for 24/7 information and suicide prevention resources for LGBTQ youth.\\n*   [Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender National Hotline](https://www.glbthotline.org/hotline.html): Call [800-273-8255](tel:800-273-8255) from 1pm – 9pm for support, information or help finding resources.\\n*   [Victims of Crime Resource Center](https://1800victims.org/): Call or text [800-842-8467](tel:800-842-8467) or [chat online](https://1800victims.org/) for information about LGTBQ rights, legal protections, and local resources.\\n\\nMore info: [Resources for emotional support and well-being](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"134"},{"Question":"Can I apply for a contact tracing position?","Answer":"Contact your [local health department](https://covid19.ca.gov/state-local-resources/) to see if they are hiring contact tracing staff.\\n\\nMore info: [Contact tracing](https://covid19.ca.gov/contact-tracing/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/contact-tracing/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"138"},{"Question":"County case metrics","Answer":"**Stable or down trending hospitalizations**\\n\\n*   Stable hospitalizations of COVID individuals on a 7-day average of daily percent change of less than 5% **OR** no more than 20 COVID hospitalizations on any single day in the past 14 days \\n\\n**Cases per population count and test positivity rate**\\n\\n*   Less than 25 new cases per 100,000 residents in the past 14 days **OR** less than 8% testing positive in the past 7 days\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"139"},{"Question":"County preparedness","Answer":"**Testing capacity** \\n\\n*   Minimum daily testing volume to test 1.5 per 1,000 residents, which can be met through a combination of testing of symptomatic individuals and targeted surveillance.  The county’s average daily testing volume for the past week must be provided.  If the county does not believe a testing volume of 1.5 per 1,000 residents is merited, justification must be provided. \\n*   Testing availability for at least 75% of residents, as measured by a specimen collection site (including established health care providers) within 30 minutes driving time in urban areas, and 60 minutes in rural areas. \\n\\n**Contact tracing** \\n\\n*   Sufficient contact tracing so public health staff work can work with a patient to help them recall everyone with whom they have had close contact during the timeframe while they may have been infectious.  For counties that have no cases, there should be at least 15 staff per 100,000 county population trained and available for contact tracing; for counties with small populations, there must be at least one staff person trained and available.  \\n\\n**Hospital surge**\\n\\n*   County (or regional) hospital capacity to accommodate a minimum surge of 35% due to COVID-19 cases in addition to providing usual care for non-COVID-19 patients.  \\n\\n**SNF disease outbreak prevention and containment**\\n\\n*   Must have plans to prevent and mitigate infections in skilled nursing facilities (SNF)\\n*   Skilled nursing facilities must have more than a 14 day supply of PPE on hand for staff, with an established process for ongoing procurement from non-state supply chains.  \\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"140"},{"Question":"County response","Answer":"*   Counties must produce plans for the following related to county-wide containment:\\n    *   Availability of temporary housing units to shelter at least 15% of county residents experiencing homelessness in case of an outbreak among this population requiring isolation and quarantine of affected individuals. The county’s plans to support individuals, including those experiencing homelessness, who are not able to properly isolate in a home setting by providing them with temporary housing (including access to a private bathroom), for the duration of the necessary isolation or quarantine period must be described.\\n\\n*   County (or regional) hospital facilities have a robust plan to protect the hospital workforce, both clinical and nonclinical, with PPE.  \\n*   Guidance for employers and essential critical infrastructure workplaces on how to structure the physical environment to protect essential workers.  \\n*   Availability of supplies (disinfectant, essential protective gear) to protect essential workers. \\n*   Each county must provide details on their plans to move further ahead in the Resilience Roadmap including which sectors and spaces will be opened, in what sequence, on what timeline.  Please specifically indicate where the plan differs from the state’s order.  Please note that this variance should not include sectors that are part of Stage 3.\\n*   County metrics that would serve as triggers for either slowing the pace through Stage 2 or tightening modifications, including the frequency of measurement, the specific actions triggered by metric changes must be described, and how the county will inform the state of emerging concerns and how it will implement early containment measures. \\n*   The county must provide details on the plan to move through opening sectors and spaces that are part of the State’s plan for Stage 2. A reminder, that this variance only covers those areas that are part of Stage 2, up to, but not including Stage 3. \\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"141"},{"Question":"Dine-in restaurants","Answer":"This [guidance for dine-in restaurants](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-dine-in-restaurants.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for dine-in restaurants](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-dine-in-restaurants.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"142"},{"Question":"Hair salons and barbershops","Answer":"This [guidance for hair salons and barbershops](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-hair-salons.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"143"},{"Question":"Casinos","Answer":"In working with tribal governments, CDPH and DIR has released guidance on how to reopen casinos with reduced risk of transmission. Tribal governments should make determinations on when to reopen based on how they align with the current local public health conditions and the statewide stage of reopening and the Governor respectfully requests that until a surrounding or neighboring local jurisdiction has progressed into Stage 3, tribal casinos remain closed.\\n\\nFollow this [guidance for casinos](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-casinos.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"144"},{"Question":"Movie theaters and family entertainment centers","Answer":"Follow this guidance for [movie theaters and family entertainment centers](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-family-entertainment.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"145"},{"Question":"Restaurants, wineries, and bars","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for restaurants, wineries, and bars](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-restaurants-bars.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"146"},{"Question":"Zoos and museums","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for zoos, museums](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-zoos-museums.pdf), galleries, and aquariums to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"147"},{"Question":"Gyms and fitness centers","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for gyms and fitness centers](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-fitness.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"148"},{"Question":"Hotels (for tourism and individual travel)","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for hotels and short term rentals](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-hotels-lodging-rentals.pdf) for tourism and individual travel to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"149"},{"Question":"Cardrooms and racetracks","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for cardrooms](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-cardrooms-racetracks.pdf), race tracks, and satellite wagering to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"150"},{"Question":"Campgrounds and outdoor recreation","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for campgrounds](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-campgrounds.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"151"},{"Question":"Personal care services","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for personal care services](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/expanded-personal-services.pdf) like nail salons, tattoo parlors, and body waxing to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nMore info: [County variance info](https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/roadmap-counties/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"152"},{"Question":"Northern California","Answer":"*   Alturas (Modoc County)\\n*   Bear Valley (Alpine County)\\n*   Bieber (Lassen County)\\n*   Bishop (Inyo County)\\n*   Bridgeport (Mono County)\\n*   Cedarville (Modoc County)\\n*   Clearlake (Lake County)\\n*   Crescent City (Del Norte County)\\n*   Daly City (San Mateo County)\\n*   Downieville (Sierra County)\\n*   Doyle (Lassen County)\\n*   East Palo Alto (San Mateo County)\\n*   Half Moon Bay (San Mateo County)\\n*   Hayfork (Trinity County)\\n*   Herlong (Lassen County)\\n*   Jackson (Amador County)\\n*   Kirkwood (Alpine and Amador Counties)\\n*   Lakeport (Lake County)\\n*   Lone Pine (Inyo County)\\n*   Loyalton (Sierra County)\\n*   Mammoth Lakes (Mono County)\\n*   Middletown (Lake County)\\n*   Napa (Napa County)\\n*   Oakland (Alameda County)\\n*   Quincy (Plumas County)\\n*   Redwood City (San Mateo County)\\n*   Sacramento (Sacramento County)\\n*   Salida (Stanislaus County)\\n*   San Francisco (San Francisco)\\n*   San Jose (Santa Clara County)\\n*   San Mateo (San Mateo County)\\n*   Stockton (San Joaquin County)\\n*   Susanville (Lassen County)\\n*   Weaverville (Trinity County)\\n*   Westwood (Lassen County)\\n*   Willow Creek (Humboldt County)\\n*   Woodfords (Alpine County)\\n*   Yosemite Valley (Mariposa County)\\n\\nMore info: [Testing and treatment](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"153"},{"Question":"Southern California","Answer":"*   Bakersfield (Kern County)\\n*   Lake Elsinore (Riverside County)\\n*   Long Beach (Los Angeles County)\\n*   Los Angeles (Los Angeles County)\\n*   Sherman Oaks (Los Angeles County)\\n\\nMore info: [Testing and treatment](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"154"},{"Question":"How do I get a drive-through test?","Answer":"There are two steps to this process: screening and testing. First, you will create an account and take the online screener. If your answers from the screener determine you are eligible at this time, you will receive details on how and where to get tested. Once tested, you’ll be informed via email or phone when your COVID-19 test results are available.\\n\\nMore info: [Testing and treatment](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"155"},{"Question":"Why am I asked to create an account for drive-through testing using Verily’s Project Baseline?","Answer":"For the Baseline COVID-19 Program to work, Verily needs a way to authenticate users to appropriately protect their information. Verily turned to Google for this service because Google Account provides best-in-class authentication. We ask that you link to an existing Google Account or create a new Google Account (which can be done with any email address). This lets Verily authenticate your account, and securely and privately contact you during the screening and testing process. All the data provided by Baseline COVID-19 Program users for screening is stored separately and not directly linked to a user’s Google Account.\\n\\nMore info: [Testing and treatment](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"156"},{"Question":"I have mild COVID-19 symptoms. How long do I have to isolate at home?","Answer":"Follow the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) guidance on [ending self-isolation](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/disposition-in-home-patients.html).\\n\\nMore info: [Testing and treatment](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"157"},{"Question":"What are the pay and benefits for California Health Corps professionals?","Answer":"Salary rates for most of the health care professionals being hired for this emergency are listed in the [CalHR Pay Scales](https://www.calhr.ca.gov/Pay%20Scales%20Library/PS_Sec_05.pdf) (pages 5.12 and 5.13). In addition, CalHR has established pay rates for medical roles that don’t have a corresponding regular classification and pay schedule, such as paramedics and EMTs. CalHR will determine specific salary and benefits after conducting a review of each application.\\n\\nMore info: [California Health Corps](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"158"},{"Question":"When can I expect to hear a response after completing my California Health Corps registration?","Answer":"Currently we anticipate the process may take up to two weeks, since an incredible number of responses are received and need to prioritize certain parts of the state, where the needs are the greatest. We will begin to contact the volunteers after verification of credentials, and based on current and anticipated needs.\\n\\nMore info: [California Health Corps](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"160"},{"Question":"How do I return to the California Health Corps application after logging out?","Answer":"Visit [https://healthcarevolunteers.ca.gov/](https://healthcarevolunteers.ca.gov/) and use the account you created while applying to correct or update any information you want.\\n\\nMore info: [California Health Corps](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"161"},{"Question":"Resources for the California Health Corps participants","Answer":"*   SNF Orientation: [SNF-Nursing-Staff-Orientation (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/SNF-Nursing-Staff-Orientation.pdf)\\n*   Program FAQ details: [CA-Health-Corps-FAQ (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/CA-Health-Corps-FAQ.pdf)\\n*   How to file a complaint: [How-to-file-a-complaint (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/How-to-file-a-complaint.pdf)\\n*   EMSA Pocket Travel Guide: [EMSA-Pocket-Travel-Guide (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/EMSA-Pocket-Travel-Guide.pdf)\\n*   Direct deposit: [std699-Direct-Deposit (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/std699-Direct-Deposit.pdf)\\n*   Travel Info: [CA-Health-Corps-Travel-Info (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/CA-Health-Corps-Travel-Info.pdf)\\n*   Travel expense claim: [Std262-Travel-Expense-Claim (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/Std262-Travel-Expense-Claim.pdf)\\n\\nMore info: [California Health Corps](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"162"},{"Question":"Agriculture and livestock","Answer":"The [guidance for the agriculture and livestock industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-agriculture.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the agriculture and livestock industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-agriculture.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"163"},{"Question":"Auto dealerships","Answer":"The [guidance for the automobile dealerships and rental operators industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-auto-dealerships.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the automobile dealerships and rental operators](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-auto-dealerships.pdf) industry in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"164"},{"Question":"Childcare","Answer":"All childcare facilities can open with necessary modifications. The updated [guidance for childcare industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-childcare.pdf) provides guidelines to minimize the spread of COVID-19 and ensure the safety of children, providers, and families. As programs begin to reopen and other programs transition from emergency childcare for essential workers to enhanced regular operations, all providers must apply new and updated policies and requirements and must update their emergency preparedness plan.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"165"},{"Question":"Communications infrastructure","Answer":"The [guidance for the communications infrastructure industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-communications.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the communications infrastructure industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-communications.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"166"},{"Question":"Construction","Answer":"This [guidance for the construction industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-construction.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the construction industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-construction.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"167"},{"Question":"Day camps","Answer":"The [guidance for day camps](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-daycamps.pdf) provides guidelines to create a plan for safe re-opening.  Implementation of these guidelines should be tailored for each setting. Implementation requires training and support for staff and adequate consideration of camper and family needs. All decisions about following these recommendations should be made in collaboration with local health officials and other authorities, and should depend on the levels of COVID-19 community transmission and the capacities of the local public health and healthcare systems, among other relevant factors.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"168"},{"Question":"Delivery services","Answer":"The [guidance for the delivery services industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-delivery-services.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the delivery services industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-delivery-services.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"169"},{"Question":"Energy and utilities","Answer":"The [guidance for the energy and utilities industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-energy.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post  the [checklist for the energy and utilities industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-energy.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"170"},{"Question":"Family friendly practices for employers","Answer":"The [guidance for family friendly practices for employers](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-familyfriendlypracticesemployers.pdf) provides guidelines for family-friendly practices to keep employees safe and be responsive to their needs in order to ensure continued productivity. As workplaces reopen, employees will require both child care supports and workplace flexibility. Work-life balance policies will become even more important and continued investment in family-friendly workplace policies by employers is critical.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"171"},{"Question":"Food packing","Answer":"The [guidance for facilities that process or pack meat, dairy, or produce](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-food-packing.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for facilities that process or pack meat, dairy or produce](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-food-packing.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"172"},{"Question":"Hotels and lodging","Answer":"This [guidance for the hotels and lodging](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-hotels.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.\\n\\nUnder the current statewide Stay-at-Home order, hotels should only open for COVID-19 mitigation and containment measures, treatment measures, providing accommodation for essential workers, or providing housing solutions, including measures to protect homeless populations.\\n\\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for Hotels and lodging](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-hotels.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"173"},{"Question":"Life sciences","Answer":"The [guidance for the life sciences industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-life-sciences.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the life sciences industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-life-sciences.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"174"},{"Question":"Limited services","Answer":"Limited Services are defined as those which do not generally require close contact. Follow this [guidance for Limited Services](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-limited-services.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nFaith-based counseling can reopen within the following parameters:\\n\\n1.  Counselling services are permissible in-person where the service cannot reasonably be practiced remotely;\\n2.  Counselling services should adopt state guidance on Limited Services, where applicable;\\n3.  This designation does not permit gatherings beyond counselling to members of a single household.\\n\\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for Limited Services](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-limited-services.pdf) in your workplace to show clients and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"175"},{"Question":"Logistics and warehousing facilities","Answer":"The [guidance for businesses operating in the logistics/warehousing industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-logistics-warehousing.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post  the [checklist for the logistics/warehousing industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-logistics-warehousing.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"176"},{"Question":"Manufacturing","Answer":"The [guidance for the manufacturing industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-manufacturing.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the manufacturing industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-manufacturing.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"177"},{"Question":"Mining and logging","Answer":"The [guidance for the mining and logging industries](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-mining-logging.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the mining and logging industries](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-mining-logging.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"178"},{"Question":"Music, film, and TV production","Answer":"Music, TV and film production may resume in California, recommended no sooner than June 12, 2020 and subject to approval by county public health officers within the jurisdictions of operations following their review of local epidemiological data including cases per 100,000 population, rate of test positivity, and local preparedness to support a health care surge, vulnerable populations, contact tracing and testing.  \\n  \\nTo reduce the risk of COVID-19 transmission, productions, cast, crew and other industry workers should abide by safety protocols agreed by labor and management, which may be further enhanced by county public health officers. Back office staff and management should adhere to [Office Workspace guidelines](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/#top) published by the California Department of Public Health and the California Department of Industrial Relations, to reduce the risk of COVID-19 transmission.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"179"},{"Question":"Office workspaces","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for office workspaces](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-office-workspaces.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers.\\n\\nFaith-based office workspaces can reopen within the following parameters:\\n\\n1.  Faith-based facilities are considered “offices” only for those employed by the organization and where the facility is their regular place of work.\\n2.  The employer should implement state guidance relating to offices before reopening the facility for employees.\\n3.  This designation does not permit gatherings of non-employees, such as the organization’s congregation.\\n\\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for office workspaces](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-office-workspaces.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"180"},{"Question":"Outdoor museums","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for outdoor museums](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-outdoor-museums.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and patrons.\\n\\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for outdoor museums](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-outdoor-museums.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"181"},{"Question":"Places of worship","Answer":"This [guidance for the places of worship](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-places-of-worship.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"182"},{"Question":"Ports","Answer":"This [guidance for the port industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-ports.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers. Review the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the port industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-ports.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"183"},{"Question":"Professional sports (without live audiences)","Answer":"Professional sports in California may resume training and competition without live audiences, recommended no sooner than June 12, 2020 and subject to approval by county public health officers within the jurisdiction of operations following their review of local epidemiological data including cases per 100,000 population, rate of test positivity, and local preparedness to support a health care surge, vulnerable populations, contact tracing and testing.  \\n  \\nTo reduce the risk of COVID-19 transmission, athletes, coaching staff, medical staff, broadcasting staff and others at sporting facilities or events should abide by COVID-19 protocols agreed by labor and management, which may be further enhanced by county public health officers. Back office staff and management should adhere to [Office Workspace guidelines](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-office-workspaces.pdf) published by the California Department of Public Health and the California Department of Industrial Relations, to reduce the risk of COVID-19 transmission. Retail staff should adhere to [Retail guidelines](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-retail.pdf) published by the California Department of Public Health and the California Department of Industrial Relations, to reduce the risk of COVID-19 transmission.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"184"},{"Question":"Public transit and intercity passenger rail","Answer":"This [guidance for public transit agencies](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-transit-rail.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for public transit agencies](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-transit-rail.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"185"},{"Question":"Real estate transaction","Answer":"This [guidance for businesses operating in the real estate industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-real-estate.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for workers.  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for the real estate industry](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-real-estate.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"186"},{"Question":"Retail","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for retailers](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-retail.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and customers.\\n\\nRetailers and libraries can re-open, along with the manufacturing and logistics sectors that support retail. Drive-in and movie theaters can re-open with additional considerations.\\n\\nRetail doesn’t include personal services such as beauty salons, but does include the sale of goods such as:\\n\\n*   Bookstores\\n*   Jewelry stores\\n*   Toy stores\\n*   Clothing and shoe stores\\n*   Home and furnishing stores\\n*   Sporting goods stores\\n*   Florists\\n\\nRetail stores identified in the [essential workforce list](https://covid19.ca.gov/essential-workforce/) can open for in-store shopping. They include:\\n\\n*   Retail facilities specializing in medical goods and supplies\\n*   Grocery stores, pharmacies, convenience stores, and other retail that sells food or beverage products, and animal/pet food\\n*   Fuel centers such as gas stations and truck stops\\n*   Hardware and building materials stores, consumer electronics, technology and appliances retail\\n\\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for retail](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-retail.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"187"},{"Question":"Schools","Answer":"This [interim guidance for schools and school-based programs](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-schools.pdf) provides guidelines to create a safer environment for student, family, and staff populations. This guidance will be updated as new data and practices emerge. The guidelines and considerations do not reflect the full scope of issues that school communities will need to address, which range from day-to-day site-based logistics to the social and emotional well-being of students and staff. Further guidance is forthcoming, including on school-based sports and extracurricular activities. All decisions about following this guidance should be made in collaboration with local health officials and other authorities.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"188"},{"Question":"Support for working families","Answer":"The [support for working families](http://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-supportworkingfamilies.pdf) guidance provides information to help you locate child care, find assistance to pay for child care, and connect you to additional supports for your family. As stay-at-home orders are lifted for additional industries to promote California’s economic recovery, the need for child care and other supports for working families increases.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"189"},{"Question":"Shopping centers","Answer":"Follow this [guidance for shopping centers](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-shopping-centers.pdf) to create a safer environment for workers and customers.  \\n  \\nInterior stores in shopping malls can do curbside pickup with modifications.  \\n  \\nReview the guidance, prepare a plan, and post the [checklist for shopping centers](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/checklist-shopping-centers.pdf) in your workplace to show customers and employees that you’ve reduced the risk and are open for business.\\n\\nMore info: [Statewide industry guidance to reduce risk](https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/)","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/industry-guidance/","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"190"},{"Question":"Can I get a free coronavirus test?","Answer":"Yes, if you qualify. More info \\n\\n[Testing and treatmeent](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/)","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"191"},{"Question":"What coronavirus/COVID-19 symptoms require immediate medical attention?","Answer":"Seek emergency medical attention if you have any of the following warning signs:\\n* Trouble breathing\\n* Persistent pain or pressure in the chest\\n* New confusion or inability to awaken\\n* Bluish lips or face\\n\\n[Testing and treatment](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/)","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"192"},{"Question":"Is there a convalescent blood plasma donation center near me?","Answer":"Please see [Donating blood plasma page](https://covid19.ca.gov/plasma/)","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"193"},{"Question":"Can a foreign medical graduate without California licence work as doctor for the California Health Corps?","Answer":"No. Please see California Health Corps page under Step 1, a valid California license is required for clinical practice (if you are a MD, DO, etc.)\\n\\n[California Health Corps](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/)","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"194"},{"Question":"Can a doctor without California license work under the California Health Corps?","Answer":"No. Please see California Health Corps page under Step 1, a valid California license is required for clinical practice (if you are a MD, DO, etc.). However, medical resident are permitted to participate in the California Health Corps.\\n\\n[California Health Corps](https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/)","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"195"},{"Question":"Are pools open? Can I go swimming?","Answer":"Community centers, including public pools, playgrounds, and picnic areas, are not permitted to operate in the State of California at this time.","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"196"},{"Question":"Can I get a massage?","Answer":"Personal services such as nail salons, tattoo parlors, and massage clinics are not permitted to operate in the State of California at this time.","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"197"},{"Question":"Can I get a tattoo?","Answer":"Personal services such as nail salons, tattoo parlors, and massage clinics are not permitted to operate in the State of California at this time.","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"198"},{"Question":"Can I go camping?","Answer":"All California State Park campgrounds are closed to help slow the spread of COVID-19. Check the [California State Park's website](https://www.parks.ca.gov/?page_id=30350) before leaving your home to find what parks are open and new visitor guidelines. Information about open outdoor areas can be found on the [public recreation page](https://covid19.ca.gov/public-recreation/).","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"199"},{"Question":"Where can I apply for unemployment?","Answer":"If you lost your job or had your hours reduced, and meet eligibility requirements, you may be eligible to receive Unemployment Insurance (UI) benefits from California’s Employment Development Department (EDD). Check the <a href=\"https://unemployment.edd.ca.gov/guide\">guide to applying for unemployment benefits</a>.","Source":"Editorial","Metadata":" ","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"false","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"200"}]